# Eliezer Talón

+41 (0) 76 447 22 78

elitalon@gmail.com

### Eliezer Talón

Software Engineer with 7+ years of experience building iOS and web applications.



Developed the MVP of Fintonic for iOS, reaching 50k downloads during the first three months and providing the foundation for the next versions.

Improved the user experience of payments and budget creation for Numbrs, increasing the ratings in the App Store by 60%.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **FIFA TMS**

iOS Engineer Zürich

JANUARY 2016 - PRESENT

Developing the iOS client for GPX, a networking tool that provides a private and secure platform for professional football stakeholders worldwide to communicate with each other.

- Built a brand new feature called *Directory*, a browsable database of football entities.
- Consolidated a continuous integration service to help QA engineers keep track of changes.

#### Centralway

iOS Engineer / Tech Lead Zürich

FEBRUARY 2014 - JANUARY 2016

Led the iOS team that built Sandbox, an application featuring a news feed and chat to support the activity of the group; afterwards joined the iOS team that builds Numbrs, a multi-banking platform to make banking convenient for end users.

- Assisted the Project Manager of Sandbox with the technical aspects of the project.
- Worked together with UX designers to develop a budget assistant tool for Numbrs.

#### Back-end Engineer Canary Islands

AUGUST 2013 - JANUARY 2014

Started working as contractor; maintained academic, a web application to coordinate the activities of the Faculty of Veterinary of ULPGC; at the same time developed a web application to assist the City Hall of Las Palmas de Gran Canaria with regulating and coordinating street markets in the city.

## Inventiaplus Software Engineer Canary Islands

JUNE 2009 - JULY 2013

Developed a variety of web and mobile applications, working directly with customers both on-site and remotely; allowed the company to expand its services after specialising in iOS development.

- Led the development of several projects, from requirements definition to actual implementation.
- Developed and maintained the IT infrastructure of the company, including virtual servers and network services.
- Organised workshops to teach CakePHP.

#### e-pyme

**Software Engineering Intern** Canary Islands

JUNE 2007 - OCTOBER 2007

Helped maintain a web application for registration and approval of civil engineering projects. Assisted system engineers to develop, test and maintain the IT infrastructure that provided services to the company.

#### PUBLIC SPEAKING

#### **App Builders Group**

Zürich

2016

"What nobody will tell you about JSON", sharing tips and best practices on when and how to choose third-party libraries for Swift development.

#### App2You

Las Palmas de Gran Canaria

2014

"Fintonic, la herramienta para controlar tus gastos", presenting the MVP of Fintonic and introducing the business model for mobile banking in Spain.

#### **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

#### Las Palmas de Gran Canaria Christian Church

2000 - 2014

Designed flyers and booklets for summer camps, concerts and other events.

#### **SKILLS**

iOS

Objective-C, Swift, Foundation, UIKit, Core Data, Auto Layout, XCTest, CocoaPods, fastlane

**Tools & methodologies** 

Git, REST, SCRUM, unit testing, continuous integration

Back-end

PHP, MySQL, CakePHP, shell-scripting (Bash, Ruby), Linux, OS X

#### **EDUCATION**

#### University of Las Palmas de Gran Canaria

MSc. Computer Engineer

2001 - 2009

Main subjects related to software design, operating systems and network administration.

 Presented a Master's Thesis on the topic of using Optical Character Recognition as a tool to automate the categorisation of news in newspapers (source code available on GitHub).

#### **OTHER INTERESTS**

Music

Played guitar in a gospel choir and a cover band

**Sports** 

Running, snowboarding, swimming, scuba diving